<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[loudjet]]></title><description><![CDATA[Becoming a Better Human - Promoting tolerance of others, compassion for the suffering, and freedom of the individual]]></description><link>http://loudjet.com</link><generator>NodeJS RSS Module</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 05:39:27 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://loudjet.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Steve Jobs Biography: Insanely Great]]></title><description><![CDATA[<h1>Steve Jobs Biography: Insanely Great</h1>
<p>My cobbled notes on the Steve Jobs biography…</p>
<p>First, one of my favorite quotes that makes my hair stand up:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The people who are crazy enough to think that they can change the
world are the ones who do.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This book has a few recurring themes:</p>
<ol>
<li>Steve Jobs is a dick and seems to be able to exploit others into
doing what he wills. This is both good and bad.</li>
<li>Steve Jobs has a reality distortion field; see #1.</li>
<li>Steve Jobs is meticulous about the design of just about anything.</li>
</ol>
<p>My notes will focus more on Steve Jobs the entrepreneur.</p>
<p>The book establishes early on that Steve Jobs has a disdain for
authority. After reading this and some of the anecdotes regarding his
family history, I felt as if Isaacson wrote part of the book for me. It
spoke to me personally. Perhaps, that means it was well written? <a href="http://daringfireball.net/linked/2011/11/15/siracusa-jobs-bio">Forget
the
haters</a>.</p>
<p>A quote about religion that resonated with me: </p>
<blockquote>
<p>The juice goes out of Christianity when it becomes too based on faith
rather than on living like Jesus or seeing the world as Jesus saw it.
I think different religions are different doors to the same house.
Sometimes, I think the house exists, and sometimes I don’t. It’s a
great mystery.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I enjoyed the early tales of Jobs seeking enlightenment and
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wisdom_in_Buddhism">prajna</a> - much <a href="http://techneur.com/post/859911519/which-is-better-the-journey-or-the-destination">like
my
journey</a>.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Coming back to America was, for me, much more of a cultural shock than
going to India. The people in the Indian countryside don’t use their
intellect like we do, they use their intuition instad, and their
intuition is far more developed than in the rest of the world.
Intuition is a very powerful thing, more powerful than intellect.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Think about that statement for a moment; think about how it relates to
products. Of course their are biases, but I think that it could be said
that making a product intuitive or one that appeals to intuition far
outweighs those that appeal to the intellect. People are not rational,
and have different levels of intellect. Products that appeal to
intellect aren’t necessarily bad, see: Vim. They are just niche
products. When a person wants to have an impact upon the world, like
Jobs, this must be considered.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>My vision was to create the first fully packaged computer. We were no
longer aiming for the handful of hobbyists who liked to assemble their
own computers, who knew how to buy transformers and keyboards. For
every one of them, there were a thousand people who would want the
machine to be ready to run.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Markkula (original investor in Apple) wrote a one page paper: “The Apple
Marketing Philosphy”:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Empathy</strong>. An intimate connection with the feelings of the customer.
We will truly understand the needs of the customer better than any
other company.\
<strong>Focus</strong>. In order to do a good job of those things that we decide to
do, we must eliminate all of the unimportant opportunities.\
<strong>Impute</strong>. People form an opinion of a company by the signals that it
conveys. People do judge a book by it’s cover.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Often attributed to Leonardo da Vinci: “Simplicity is the ultimate
sophistication.” This became one of the maxim’s for Jobs’s design
philosophy.</p>
<p>The Apple II, Lisa, Xerox PARC, and Macintosh stories set the stage for
Job’s core beliefs on products:</p>
<ol>
<li>Design leads engineering. That is to say, the design dictates
everything. Engineering must find a way to make it work with the
design. Most companies are backwards in this regard.</li>
<li>Simple products are easier to use.</li>
<li>Customers don’t know what they want, Apple must show them.</li>
<li>For the best product experience, Apple must own it end-to-end.
Hardware and software in contrast to the PC environment where
Microsoft just owns the operating system.</li>
</ol>
<p>On competition…</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Steve had a way of motivating by looking at the bigger picture. Jobs
thought of himself as an artist and he encourage others to think this
way too. His goal was never to make a lot of money or to be
competition, it was to do the greatest thing possible or even a little
greater.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Does it feel to you like companies get competition all wrong? They are
so focused on what their competition is doing, instead of just being the
best at what they can be. Companies lose focus by doing this. </p>
<p>The book doesn’t conclude this, but I wonder if part of the reason he
did this was to instill cultural pride in his employees. If they feel
they must focus on these details, then they’ll ingrain this philosophy
in their heads day in and day out. Thus, being a bit more meticulous
about their crafts.</p>
<p>On employees…</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I learned over the years that A-plus players like to work together,
and they don’t like it if you tolerate B work.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>So true.</p>
<p>Jobs had incessant demands for perfectionism in things that most people
won’t care about. Two examples:</p>
<ol>
<li>The inside of the cases and how Jobs wanted them to look neat and
clean.</li>
<li>The way his factories look and how he detailed he wanted machinery
to look and operate. Even positioning.</li>
</ol>
<p>Rebel Spirit…</p>
<blockquote>
<p>It’s better to be a pirate than to join the navy.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Market Research when asked about launching the Mac…</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Did Alexander Graham Bell do any market research when inventing the
telephone?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>On Focus…</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Deciding what not to do is as important as deciding what do to. That’s
true for companies, and it’s true for products.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>On Design…</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Design is the fundamental soul of a man-made creation that ends up
expressing itself in successive outer layers.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Overall, I really enjoyed this book. I felt as if I was taking a tour of
the mind of Steve Jobs and what made him tick.</p>
<p>Now, imagine what a person could do if they could lead in a more humble
manner, giving their employees credit, not stealing the spotlight, but
not being afraid of calling people out on their bullshit and pushing
them to their limits? Imagine if this person had a rebellious attitude
and a disdain for authority. What if this person had an overwhelming
desire to be honest, even at his own expense? Imagine if this person had
a love of simplicity and art. Imagine that this person is driven with a
passion to deliver maximum impact on improving people’s lives. Could
this person change the world? We’ll see.</p>
<p>-JP</p>
]]></description><link>http://loudjet.com/a/steve-jobs-biography-insanely-great/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://loudjet.com/a/steve-jobs-biography-insanely-great/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[JP Richardson]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2011 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Steve Jobs 1955-2011: Sharing His Message]]></title><description><![CDATA[<h1>Steve Jobs 1955-2011: Sharing His Message</h1>
<p><img src="http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lsnf6phqdf1qzbc4f.png" alt=""></p>
<p>I pulled into the driveway after I had just picked up my son Chris from
CCD. I told him that Steve Jobs had died. “Who is that?” he said. I was
a bit surprised that he didn’t know who he was; other than Jesus, Steve
Jobs has been one the most influential persons in my life. [Yes, I may
have subtly compared Steve Jobs to Jesus :p]. I wanted to share a few of
his quotes with Chris.</p>
<p>The first are from his <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=D1R-jKKp3NA">Stanford commencement
speech</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Remembering that I’ll be dead soon is the most important tool I’ve
ever encountered to help me make the big choices in life. Because
almost everything — all external expectations, all pride, all fear of
embarrassment or failure - these things just fall away in the face of
death, leaving only what is truly important. Remembering that you are
going to die is the best way I know to avoid the trap of thinking you
have something to lose. You are already naked. There is no reason not
to follow your heart.</p>
<p>…</p>
<p>No one wants to die. Even people who want to go to heaven don’t want
to die to get there. And yet death is the destination we all share. No
one has ever escaped it. And that is as it should be, because Death is
very likely the single best invention of Life. It is Life’s change
agent. It clears out the old to make way for the new. Right now the
new is you, but someday not too long from now, you will gradually
become the old and be cleared away. Sorry to be so dramatic, but it is
quite true.</p>
<p>Your time is limited, so don’t waste it living someone else’s life.
Don’t be trapped by dogma — which is living with the results of other
people’s thinking. Don’t let the noise of others’ opinions drown out
your own inner voice. And most important, have the courage to follow
your heart and intuition. They somehow already know what you truly
want to become. Everything else is secondary.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is an important thought to keep in mind as much as possible. We
will all die. When faced with death, we forget the minutia of life but
remember what is important. This should be done daily.</p>
<p>As I tucked Chris into bed, I said to him:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Those who are crazy enough to believe that they can change the world
are the ones that actually do.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This quote came from an <a href="http://techneur.com/post/1035350505/steve-jobs-lesson-on-marketing-values-and-belief">old Steve Jobs
presentation</a>.</p>
<p>Much has been said about how we probably heard the news about<a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2011/10/05/president-obama-passing-steve-jobs-he-changed-way-each-us-sees-world">Steve
Jobs’s death via his
products</a>.
But consider this, Steve has given us wonderful products, wonderful
products that we use to improve our lives. Now, <a href="http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2011/10/a-eulogy-of-action.html">what will you do with
these
products</a>
to make a difference in the lives of others and to maybe even change the
world?</p>
<p>If you enjoyed this, you might also enjoy:</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="http://techneur.com/post/9374819200/saddened-by-steves-departure">Saddened by Steve’s
Departure</a></li>
<li><a href="http://techneur.com/post/1035350505/steve-jobs-lesson-on-marketing-values-and-belief">Steve Jobs Lesson on Marketing: Values and
Belief</a></li>
<li><a href="http://techneur.com/post/675685717/steve-jobs-henry-ford">Steve Jobs is This Century’s Henry
Ford</a></li>
</ol>
<p>Follow me on Twitter: <a href="http://twitter.com/jprichardson">@jprichardson</a></p>
<p>-JP</p>
]]></description><link>http://loudjet.com/a/steve-jobs-1955-2011-sharing-his-message/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://loudjet.com/a/steve-jobs-1955-2011-sharing-his-message/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[JP Richardson]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Do or Do Not; There Is No Try]]></title><description><![CDATA[<h1>Do or Do Not; There Is No Try</h1>
<p><img src="http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lrzhmzPr721qzbc4f.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p>Do you remember that seen in Star Wars where Master Yoda is training
Luke to become a Jedi? Luke doesn’t believe in himself and he claims
that he is <em>trying</em>.</p>
<p>Yoda then says “Do or do not; there is no try.”</p>
<p>Do you want to quit smoking?</p>
<p>Do you want to live a healthy lifestyle?</p>
<p>Do you want to be a successful entrepreneur?</p>
<p>There is no <em>try</em>.</p>
<p>The word ‘try’ is an excuse. You cannot ‘try’ to quit smoking. You
cannot try to become a successful entrepreneur. You know what you need
to do. You need to make the conscious decision and effort to do it.</p>
<p>To be a successful entrepreneur is as simple as this:</p>
<ol>
<li>Identify a problem.</li>
<li>Build a solution to solve that problem.</li>
<li>Charge money for it.</li>
</ol>
<p>I realize that this is a bit of an oversimplification. But, there is no
‘try’. You should just remove that word from your vocabulary.</p>
<p>Do or do not. There is no try.</p>
<p>-JP</p>
]]></description><link>http://loudjet.com/a/do-or-do-not-there-is-no-try/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://loudjet.com/a/do-or-do-not-there-is-no-try/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[JP Richardson]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2011 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[We Should...]]></title><description><![CDATA[<h1>We Should...</h1>
<p><img src="http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lrezvrTMXf1qzbc4f.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p>How often do you run into someone that you use to be close friends and
you have a dialogue that is similar to this:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You: How have you been?</p>
<p>Them: Good! Good… how have you been?</p>
<p>You: Oh, good… so what’s new?</p>
<p>Them: Oh you know… same old… we should get together sometime for lunch
or something.</p>
<p>You: Ya, let’s do.</p>
<p>Them: OK, well it was nice seeing you…</p>
<p>You: You too… take care.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>How do you feel after a conversation like this? Do you feel like you
have renewed your connection with this person? It seems to me that a lot
of conversations like this take place solely because it might be
considered socially rude to not acknowledge the person. Maybe the intent
of the statement “we should get together” is sincere?</p>
<p>A lot of people in my life have thrown out “we should” statements, but
with no firm date set. “Hey man… it was great meeting you at that
conference, we should Skype sometime” or “Hey, we should get some
cocktails sometime.” I’m sure they happen all of the time in your life
as well. Maybe you say them a lot?</p>
<p>Recently, I ran into an old colleague at the gym. We had a bit of small
chit-chat and I threw out the “we should get some lunch” line, I was
even being sincere about it. A few weeks passed. Shit, no lunch. One
day, I sent him an email and said “want to do lunch?” He couldn’t, and
replied that he was busy for awhile. Not a big deal.</p>
<p>The important take away is this: it’s really important to consider your
interactions with others. If you catch yourself saying the “we should”
lines, ask yourself if you’re being sincere. If you are, set a date at
that moment… if it doesn’t work that’s OK too. When it really comes down
to it, if you really care to meet someone, you’ll make it a priority.
They’ll do the same for you. If the meeting doesn’t happen, you should
probably just accept that this person isn’t a priority to you or you
might not be a priority to them. That’s OK too.</p>
<p>If you’re not sincere about meeting this person, please don’t throw out
a “we should” line. You’ll save everyone, including yourself, a bit of
guilt about the meeting not happening.</p>
<p>What are your thoughts?</p>
<p>You might also enjoy:</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="http://techneur.com/post/9251361615/youre-only-as-good-as-your-word">You’re Only as Good as Your
Word</a></li>
<li><a href="http://techneur.com/post/4393309779/fear-and-loved-ones">Fear and Loved
Ones</a></li>
<li><a href="http://techneur.com/post/3602541949/life-is-about-maximizing-the-happiness-function">Life is About Maximizing the Happiness
Function</a></li>
</ol>
<p>Follow me on Twitter: <a href="http://twitter.com/jprichardson">@jprichardson</a></p>
<p>-JP</p>
]]></description><link>http://loudjet.com/a/we-should/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://loudjet.com/a/we-should/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[JP Richardson]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2011 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Forget the Shiny Tech, Focus on the Customer Experience]]></title><description><![CDATA[<h1>Forget the Shiny Tech, Focus on the Customer Experience</h1>
<p><img src="http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lqsxc4Ipo11qzbc4f.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p>I’m always amazed when I discover a new piece of technology or software.
Usually, thousands of business ideas start pouring into my head on how I
can build a cool product. Most recently, the thought of
<a href="http://www.twilio.com/">Twilio</a>, <a href="http://mailgun.net/">Mailgun</a>, and
<a href="http://sendgrid.com/">Sendgrid</a> came to mind. </p>
<p>An internal dialogue raged on in my mind:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“SMS and email are some of the most ubiquitous communication tools,
not to mention very pervasive.”</p>
<p> ”What could I build quickly to monetize and spread virally?”</p>
<p>“Focus, you fool…”</p>
<p>“You’re in the process of selling <a href="http://reflect7.com">one company</a>
and you just <a href="http://gitpilot.com">started another</a>. Plus, no one
really cares about how you’re using cool tech.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>And then I dropped the thought.</p>
<p>This has happened to me time and time again. In fact, that’s how
Reflect7 was founded. I knew the iPhone would be hot. I knew that
consumers would purchase them by the ton. I just didn’t know what apps
to develop for it yet. Eventually we settled on sports’ apps, but we
didn’t consider the customer experience until the end.</p>
<p>I finally had this realization of all of this when I stumbled upon this
video:</p>
<p>It was Steve Jobs who made it crystal clear as to what I had done. I was
thinking a lot about the technology and how I could sell that, rather
than consider customer problems and how I could build products that
delivered a superb experience. This is what
<a href="http://gitpilot.com">Gitpilot</a> will do.</p>
<p>You might also enjoy:</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="http://techneur.com/post/3068783134/customers-demand-native-for-mobile-apps">Customers Demand Native for Mobile
Apps</a></li>
<li><a href="http://techneur.com/post/3031110881/great-artists-simplify">Great Artists
Simplify</a></li>
<li><a href="http://techneur.com/post/1313633370/apple-sucks-at-upgrades">Apple Sucks at
Upgrades</a></li>
</ol>
<p>Follow me on Twitter: @jprichardson</p>
<p>-JP</p>
]]></description><link>http://loudjet.com/a/forget-the-shiny-tech-focus-on-the-customer-experience/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://loudjet.com/a/forget-the-shiny-tech-focus-on-the-customer-experience/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[JP Richardson]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Big Success Requires Accomplishing Small Goals]]></title><description><![CDATA[<h1>Big Success Requires Accomplishing Small Goals</h1>
<p><img src="http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lqqv0mmcRi1qzbc4f.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p>I often fall victim to this. I’m very ambitious; typically I have many
projects and goals running concurrently. It’s important to remember that
you must break down your goals into smaller goals.</p>
<ul>
<li>Want to run a marathon? Start by running 1 mile, and then 2 miles,
etc.</li>
<li>Want to make a 1 million dollars? Learn how to make 1000 dollars
first.</li>
<li>Want to <a href="http://techneur.com/post/2958461062/i-will-write-an-ebook">write a
book</a>?
Use <a href="http://www.literatureandlatte.com/scrivener.php">Scrivener</a> to
write one paragraph a day.</li>
<li>Want to write an autobiography? Write one blog post every day.</li>
</ul>
<p>It sounds so easy, but yet it’s tough to do this. Lately, I’ve been
using the todo iPhone app <a href="http://tomorrow.do/">Do It (Tomorrow)</a> to
break up my goals into actionable tasks each day. So far, it’s worked
out great.</p>
<p>How do you accomplish your big goals? Do you use any specific tools?</p>
<p>You might also enjoy:</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="http://techneur.com/post/4159105323/the-two-device-productivity-solution">Two-Device Productivity
Solution</a></li>
<li><a href="http://techneur.com/post/3900181315/what-the-successful-will-do-that-you-wont">What the Successful Will Do That You
Won’t</a></li>
<li><a href="http://techneur.com/post/3484249692/dont-let-brain-prevent-your-goals">Don’t Let Your Brain Prevent You From Your
Goals</a></li>
<li><a href="http://techneur.com/post/3178749659/unmotivated-get-some-layups">Umotiviated? Get Some
Layups</a></li>
</ol>
<p>Follow me on Twitter: <a href="http://twitter.com/jprichardson">@jprichardson</a></p>
<p>-JP</p>
]]></description><link>http://loudjet.com/a/big-success-requires-accomplishing-small-goals/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://loudjet.com/a/big-success-requires-accomplishing-small-goals/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[JP Richardson]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2011 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sometimes It Doesn't Matter What the Contract States]]></title><description><![CDATA[<h1>Sometimes It Doesn&#39;t Matter What the Contract States</h1>
<p><img src="http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lqpbv6HVVm1qzbc4f.gif" alt=""></p>
<p>Disclaimer: at this time, I can’t write about the details behind the
blog post. I will however in the near future.</p>
<p>Recently, I entered into a negotiation to exchange some software for
cash. That is, I would develop some software and in return, the prospect
would give me cash. Pretty straightforward.</p>
<p>The prospect read over the detailed contract and enthusiastically signed
it. A video of the software working was sent. Positive feedback was
received. The first wire transfer came. All was well. </p>
<p>When the software was delivered, the prospect was disappointed. They
stated that a few things were missing that they didn’t expect to be
missing. Despite the fact that the video showed that these features were
missing and the contract detailed what was included in the software
deliverable, they were still disappointed. It was clear that their
perspective and feelings weren’t malevolent.</p>
<p>I feel as if I’m left with two choices:</p>
<ol>
<li>Acquiesce and change the software to meet their expectations.</li>
<li>Adhere to the contract.</li>
</ol>
<p>Both sides have advantages and disadvantages. However, you need to do
what you think is right considering all circumstances. This could be
either #1 or #2.</p>
<p>Think about what you put into your contracts. Do you need to explicitly
point out anything while you’re meeting with your prospects? How can you
make your contracts crystal clear? What could be misinterpreted?</p>
<p>You might also enjoy:</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="http://techneur.com/post/9333627575/restaurant-industry-teach-business-customer-expectations">What the Restaurant Industry Can Teach Us About Business: Customer
Expectations</a></li>
<li><a href="http://techneur.com/post/3565725520/to-stand-out-you-must-dazzle-your-customers">To Stand Out, You Must Dazzle Your
Customers</a></li>
<li><a href="http://techneur.com/post/3318455009/consider-customer-motivations">Consider Customer
Motivations</a></li>
</ol>
<p>Follow me on Twitter: <a href="http://twitter.com/jprichardson">@jprichardson</a></p>
<p>-JP</p>
]]></description><link>http://loudjet.com/a/sometimes-it-doesnt-matter-what-the-contract-states/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://loudjet.com/a/sometimes-it-doesnt-matter-what-the-contract-states/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[JP Richardson]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2011 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Saddened by Steve's Departure]]></title><description><![CDATA[<h1>Saddened by Steve&#39;s Departure</h1>
<p><img src="http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lqhmd2mPpd1qzbc4f.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p>Who would have expected that many would be saddened by a CEO’s departure
from a company? I wouldn’t. But on many of the net forums, people are
expressing a bit of melancholy. I feel the same.</p>
<p>It’s not because Steve is some big, bad, powerful man [he is]… no, it’s
because Steve took Apple from the brink of bankruptcy to briefly being
the most valuable company in the world (currently the 2nd behind Exxon
Mobile). He did this all while giving us products that we as consumers
love.</p>
<p>You see, Apple represented what we love about a good story. Apple was
David the underdog. Microsoft was the evil goliath that could not be
defeated. Apple innovated. They help to revolutionize the music
industry, the computer industry, and the smartphone. I hope that they
are just getting started.</p>
<p>As an entrepreneur, Steve Jobs represents exactly what an entrepreneur
should be. One who is focused on the present while simultaneously
holding a vision. One who cares about simplicity and not just producing
another “me-to” product. One who wants to change lives.</p>
<p>I truly believe that history will remember him as this century’s Henry
Ford. Or better yet, he has set a new standard, one that I’ll always be
inspired from.</p>
<p>Farewell.</p>
<p>Read more from other new’s sources:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://daringfireball.net/2011/08/resigned">Resigned</a> [Daring
Fireball]</li>
<li><a href="http://finance.yahoo.com/news/Steve-Jobs-Resigns-as-CEO-of-bw-19285464.html?x=0&amp;.v=1">Steve Jobs Resigns as CEO of
Apple</a>
[Yahoo News]</li>
<li><a href="http://blogs.wsj.com/deals/2011/08/24/steve-jobs-resigns-as-apple-ceo/">Steve Jobs Resigns as Apple
CEO</a>
[Wall Street Journal]</li>
<li><a href="http://blogs.wsj.com/digits/2011/08/24/steve-jobss-best-quotes/">Steve Jobs’s Best
Quotes</a>
[Wall Street Journal]</li>
<li><a href="http://www.cringely.com/2011/08/cupertino-two-step/">Cupertino
Two-Step</a>
[Cringley]</li>
<li><a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2011/08/25/steve-jobs-resigns_n_935940.html#s338918">How the iPod Changed My
Life</a>
[Huffington Post]</li>
</ul>
<p>You might also enjoy:</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="http://techneur.com/post/1035350505/steve-jobs-lesson-on-marketing-values-and-belief">Steve Jobs Lesson on Marketing: Values and
Beliefs</a></li>
<li><a href="http://techneur.com/post/675685717/steve-jobs-henry-ford">Steve Jobs Is This Century’s Henry
Ford</a></li>
</ol>
<p>Follow me on Twitter: <a href="http://twitter.com/jprichardson">@jprichardson</a></p>
<p>-JP</p>
]]></description><link>http://loudjet.com/a/saddened-by-steves-departure/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://loudjet.com/a/saddened-by-steves-departure/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[JP Richardson]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2011 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[What the Restaurant Industry Can Teach Us About Business: Customer Expectations]]></title><description><![CDATA[<h1>What the Restaurant Industry Can Teach Us About Business: Customer Expectations</h1>
<p><img src="http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lqfrquH7C21qzbc4f.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p>A colleague of mine dropped by my office to share his wonderful dining
experience at the <a href="http://www.bonefishgrill.com/">Bonefish Grill
restaurant</a>. This colleague and I like to
banter about our dining experiences; we use to agree that the Bonefish
Grill was one of the best dining experiences. I should be clear, I’ve
never had a bad dining experience at the Bonefish Grill. It’s just been
inconsistent.</p>
<p>The first time that I went to the Bonefish Grill, I walked into to the
restaurant with my wife and I could smell the aroma of fresh seafood.
The entry area, where the bar resides, was dimly lit like that of a
college bar. It was packed with people like a college bar too, albeit
not in a manner liked you’d expect; it was comfortable. Conversation was
everywhere, not too loud, not too quiet. Perfect. The night was ripe for
an excellent date.</p>
<p>My wife and I were lucky enough to score some seats at the bar while we
waited for a table. The bar tender promptly took our order for drinks.
Two small TVs were in the bar area. Just enough to check the score of
the game, but not enough to distract a table from intimate conversation.
The bar tender brought over a shrimp appetizer, Bang Bang Shrip,
courtesy of the house. “We call this: making friends” he said. Very
rarely does a restaurant give away food to patrons without reason. They
set themselves up well. Even better, the shrimp was delicious.</p>
<p>Finally our pager buzzed and we were able to get a seat. The attentive
server took our order as if we were her only concern, almost like a
private butler. It was amazing. We topped the night off with a dessert.</p>
<p>I walked out of the Bonefish Grill feeling that I had one of the best
dining experiences ever. At least, the best in Nebraska.</p>
<p>The restaurant had just become my favorite restaurant. I was now their
evangelist. Almost like a Jesus spreading the gospel, but not about
eternal life, but the gospel of the freshest and most delicious seafood
the Midwest would ever see.</p>
<p>The second and third time that I went there. The experience was just
average. It wasn’t bad, just average. Slow staff. Messed up sides, etc.
I expect this sort of stuff to happen at Applebee’s, not my beloved
Bonefish.</p>
<p>The restaurant became just another restaurant to me.</p>
<p>As I was writing this, I’m reminded of when I use to work as a cook at
the local restaurant <a href="http://www.lazlosbreweryandgrill.com/">Lazlos</a> 12
years ago. When I was packing up an order, I put an extra serving of
french fries for a to-go order. The owner Jay Jarvis saw this. “What are
you doing?” he said. “I wanted to put a smile on their face.”
I enthusiastically replied. He then told me that I had put too much
fries in the order; I was just thinking that he was being a cheap owner.
He then went on to say that the next cook might not put in as much for
that same customer. The customer will feel let down. What matters is
“consistency”, he said. That was my first real lesson in consistency and
customer expectations.</p>
<p>So many restaurants struggle with this. Maybe they don’t train their
staff enough to think about providing a consistent experience?</p>
<p>I didn’t write this article to complain about
restaurant inconsistencies, but rather to get you to think about the
experience you’re delivering to your customers. How can you be more
consistent? What tools and processes can you implement to improve this?</p>
<p>But don’t forget about the <a href="http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2010/12/a-paradox-of-expectations.html">paradox of
expectations</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Better than expected might be the level of quality that’s necessary to
succeed. Of course, once that becomes the standard, the expectation is
reset. - Seth Godin</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Seth also
<a href="http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2011/01/raising-expectations-and-then-dashing-them.html">writes</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Have you noticed how upbeat the ads for airlines and banks are?</p>
<p>Judging from the billboards and the newspaper ads, you might be led to
believe that Delta is actually a better airline, one that cares. Or
that your bank has flexible people eager to bend the rules to help you
succeed.</p>
<p>At one level, this is good advertising, because it tells a story that
resonates. We want Delta to be the airline it says it is, and so we
give them a try.</p>
<p>The problem is this: ads like this actually decrease user
satisfaction. If the ad leads to expect one thing and we don’t get it,
we’re more disappointed than if we had gone in with no real
expectations at all. Why this matters: if word of mouth is the real
advertising, then what you’ve done is use old-school ad techniques to
actually undercut any chance you have to generate new-school results.</p>
<p>So much better to invest that same money in delighting and embracing
the customers you already have.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Think about this. Be consistent.</p>
<p>You might also enjoy:</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="http://techneur.com/post/3565725520/to-stand-out-you-must-dazzle-your-customers">To Stand Out, You Must Dazzle Your
Customers</a></li>
<li><a href="http://techneur.com/post/1591453730/the-power-of-the-apology">The Power of the
Apology</a></li>
<li><a href="http://techneur.com/post/564894016/hey-taco-johns-go-f-ck-yourselves-a-failure-to">Hey Taco Johns, Go F*ck Yourself: A Failure to Understand Customer
Mindshare</a></li>
</ol>
<p>Follow me on Twitter: <a href="http://twitter.com/jprichardson">@jprichardson</a></p>
<p>-JP</p>
]]></description><link>http://loudjet.com/a/restaurant-industry-teach-business-customer-expectations/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://loudjet.com/a/restaurant-industry-teach-business-customer-expectations/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[JP Richardson]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2011 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[What Does Your App Do Again?]]></title><description><![CDATA[<h1>What Does Your App Do Again?</h1>
<p><img src="http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lqc4nkJtnh1qzbc4f.png" alt=""></p>
<p>Dear Fellow Entrepreneurs:</p>
<p>When sending out a launching announcement, please include a blurb to
remind your mailing list users what your app does again and why we
signed up in the first place. This would really help us to remember in
our busy lives how your app can help <a href="http://www.jwz.org/doc/groupware.html">get your users
laid</a>.</p>
<p>Your friend,</p>
<p>JP</p>
<p>Seriously though, this happens a lot. Most recently, this happend when
<a href="http://bushi.do">Bushido</a> sent me such a welcome invite. I had no clue
what Bushido was as I had probably signed up months ago. Fortunately,
this opened up for a nice dialogue with the
<a href="https://twitter.com/#!/sgrove">founder</a> who agreed with the point.</p>
<p>Some get it right though. BufferApp’s founder <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/joelgascoigne">Joel
Gascoigne</a> did this when he
validated his app. Joel
<a href="http://techneur.com/post/3583222706/a-real-mvp-tale">writes</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>What I did with Buffer is treat the emails as people who were happy
for me to get in touch and discuss the idea with and whether it solved
a problem for them. As soon as someone put their email in the “you
caught us early” page, I sent out an email which was from my own email
address and shared more details about the product which weren’t on the
landing page. It also ended with a very welcoming paragraph explaining
that I needed their help to shape the product into something truly
useful. This triggered off a lot of communication and let me ask
people what a fair price would be for example so I could decide on my
pricing, and also decide on the priority of some features. In my
previous startup I did the right thing of launching early but I made
the mistake of having around 6000 users and never asking any of them
what they thought about the product and whether it solved a problem
for them.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>So, attach a blurb in your launch email. Even better, tell your
potential users how this app improves their life. I know that I’ll
remember this point when we launch <a href="http://gitpilot.com">Gitpilot</a>.</p>
<p>You might also enjoy:</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="http://techneur.com/post/3583222706/a-real-mvp-tale">A Real MVP
Tale</a></li>
<li><a href="http://techneur.com/post/3565725520/to-stand-out-you-must-dazzle-your-customers">To Stand Out, You Must Dazzle Your
Customers</a></li>
<li><a href="http://techneur.com/post/3299224033/your-language-to-your-customers">Your Language to Your
Customers</a></li>
</ol>
<p>Follow me on Twitter: <a href="http://twitter.com/jprichardson">@jprichardson</a></p>
<p>-JP</p>
]]></description><link>http://loudjet.com/a/what-does-your-app-do-again/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://loudjet.com/a/what-does-your-app-do-again/</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[JP Richardson]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2011 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>